John William

Full Stack Developer

575-257-0832

? IRELAND

@ johnwilliam199024@gmail.com



SUMMARY

Senior fullstack developer with over 7 years of hands-on experience in website development with React-redux, MERN, Node.js, MongoDb etc.

Extensive knowledge of back-end and front-end development with majority of modern web frameworks.

Skills in App development with 5+ years of experience as freelancer and in some companys.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

Imaginary Cloud

= 12/2020 - 12/2022

San Francisco, CA

Software Development

- Completed detailed programming and development tasks for front-end public and internal websites as well as challenging back-end server code. (NodeJS, MERN, MEAN, Ruby on Rails)
- Carried out quality assurance tests to discover errors and optimize usability.
- Designed and updated layouts to meet usability and performance requirements. (converting Figma or PSD to React)
- Developed and integrated custom themes with Next.js, Material-UI, and Type\$cript.
- Transferred legacy websites using modern front end technologies like React, Vue, and Nextjs,

Software Engineer

Yellow Systems

= 10/2016 - 12/2017

San Francisco, CA Business-First Approach to Software Development

- Produced stunning visual elements of web applications by translating UI/UX design wireframes into code while producing high-quality, reusable markup using HTML5 and CSS3.
- Designed and implemented front-end architecture to support user interface concepts with 100% accuracy.
- Expanded features, refined code, and improved processes, producing smoother operations and enhancing user engagement.
- Developed several internal systems comprising order entry/management tools, conversion/ revenue reporting, and production workflow tracking, as well as design custom REST APIs built in Laravel PHP, NodeJS, and Django.

Mobile Developer

Sidebench

=== 12/2018 - 12/2020

Santa Monica, CA

Mobile Development

- Built +30 mobile apps (booking, school management, dating, music, relay, renting) with react-native and flutter.
- Deployed to the app store and Google app store.
- I built 10 websites (blogging, dating, renting, booking) using vue & laravelstack, MERN & MEAN stack.
- Deployed using cpanel, digital ocean, aws

SKILLS

React Vue Next.js Material-Ul

Node.js Ruby MERN

React-native flutter

Block-chain

STRENGTHS

Ecommerce

Company projects related to blockchain and crypto is my favorite tasks.



Building Front-End Page with React-Redux Amazingly Is My Talent.

LANGUAGES

English

Native

ACHIEVEMENTS



Mobile App

https://biteyou.io/ https://www.bitcoinsv.com/



Front-end

https://milos-zivkovic.netlify.app/

EDUCATION

Concurrent B.S. in computer science

Kansas State University

= 02/2015 - 04/2017

University of BelgradeBachelor's degree (remote)

Kansas State University

= 12/2017

